Guide to the Norman Macleod Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Family Papers, 1905-1981; Series V; 0.83; (2 boxes)
  - Alice Wicklund Mills papers, 1905-1981; 8 (Box 67, Folder 859-866)
    Includes vital records and papers left to Norman Macleod after the death of Alice Wicklund Mills (Norman Wicklund Macleod's mother).
  - Those First Affections, (Autobiography of Alice Wicklund Mills), undated; 2 (Box 67, Folder 867-868)
  - Macleod Family papers, 1926-1977; 18 (Box 68, Folder 869-886)
  - Scotland and Clan Macleod Society, reference material, 1954-1977 (Box 68, Folder 887)
  - Macleod, Norman. Drawing of Norman Griffith Macleod (photocopy of a 1951 drawing), undated
- Teaching Records, 1969-1976; Series VI; 0.63; (2 boxes)
  Teaching Records consist chiefly of student papers written in Norman Macleod's classes taught at Pembroke State University. Also included are memoranda, correspondence, and other records relating to the Pembroke State University Department of English, and course catalogs that document courses taught by Norman Macleod at several institutions.
  - Course catalogs, 1939-1965 (Box 69, Folder 888)
  - Student Papers, 1969-1973; 6 (Box 69, Folder 889-894)
  - Pembroke University Department of English records, 1971-1976 (Box 70, Folder 895)
- Photographs, 1905-1980; Series VII; 1.25; (3 boxes)
  Arranged alphabetically by subject.
  This series consists of photographic prints of Norman Macleod as well as family members, friends, colleagues and associates.
  - Aldrich, Myrl, 1973 (Box 71, Folder 896)
  - Briarcliff Quarterly staff members, 1946-1947 (Box 71, Folder 897)
  - Butler, Harriet Holmes, 1971 (Box 71, Folder 898)
  - Bynner, Witter, 1935 (Box 71, Folder 899)
  - Carmon, Walt and Frances Strauss, 1931 (Box 71, Folder 900)
  - Colleagues and associates, 1974-1975 (Box 71, Folder 901)
  - Conroy, Jack, 1969 (Box 71, Folder 902)
  - Daganet, Ken, undated (Box 71, Folder 903)
  - Dalmas, Victor, 1975 (Box 71, Folder 904)
  - Dawes, Sally, 1969 (Box 71, Folder 905)
  - Edinburgh, Scotland, 1974 (Box 71, Folder 906)
  - Fletcher, Dorothy, 1969 (Box 71, Folder 907)
  - "Fort Macleod," Taos, New Mexico, 1958-1960 (Box 71, Folder 908)
  - Foster, Grace and Ray, 1974 (Box 71, Folder 909)
  - Garson, Greer and Alva Simpson, undated (Box 71, Folder 910)
  - Gold, Michael, 1968 (Box 71, Folder 911)
  - Gould, Joe, 1969 (Box 71, Folder 912)
  - Graham, W. S., 1974 (Box 71, Folder 913)
  - Greenwich Village "House of Genius,", 1938 (Box 71, Folder 914)
  - Hale, Dr. Charles Brockway, undated (Box 71, Folder 915)
  - Harris, Cathy, 1973-1980 (Box 71, Folder 916)
  - Hamza, Aziz, and Norman Macleod, 1964 (Box 71, Folder 917)
  - Hodgson, Gerald L., 1935-1956 (Box 71, Folder 918)
  - Horace Gregory Award party, 1973 (Box 71, Folder 919)
  - Hotvedt, Kris, 1969 (Box 71, Folder 920)
  - Ignatow, Yaedi Elizabeth, 1969-1971 (Box 71, Folder 921)
  - Inge, William with Ann and Norman Griffith Macleod, 1949 (Box 71, Folder 922)
  - Iraq, 1969 (Box 71, Folder 923)
    Includes snapshots of Ctesiphon, Iraq, taken while Macleod was teaching at the University of Baghdad.
  - Koch, Vivienne, 1931-1945 (Box 71, Folder 924)
  - MacDiarmid, Hugh, 1974
  - Macleod, Ann Clarke and children, 1951-1959 (Box 71, Folder 925)
  - Macleod, Catherine Stuart and Jocelyn, 1927-1951, 1976 (Box 71, Folder 926)
  - Macleod family, 1976, 1979 (Box 71, Folder 927)
  - Macleod, Norman Griffith, 1950-1981 (Box 71, Folder 928)
  - Macleod, Norman Wicklund, 1910-1959; 2 (Box 71, Folder 929-930)
  - Macleod, Norman Wicklund (Continued), 1960-1975; 2 (Box 72, Folder 931-932)
  - Macleod, Skye, 1950-1976; 2 (Box 72, Folder 933-934)
  - Mills, Alice Wicklund, 1905-1963 (Box 72, Folder 935)
  - Mills, Robert, 1930-1947 (Box 72, Folder 936)
  - Mills, William Park, undated (Box 72, Folder 937)
  - Morang, Alfred, 1956 (Box 72, Folder 938)
  - Nassen, Doctor H. L., 1945 (Box 72, Folder 939)
  - Owen, Guy, 1970, 1973 (Box 72, Folder 940)
  - Pauli, Kenneth W., 1952-1973 (Box 72, Folder 941)
  - Pearson, Norman Holmes, 1973 (Box 72, Folder 942)
  - Peck, Ruth, 1975 (Box 73, Folder 943)
  - Pembroke Magazine, 1975 (Box 73, Folder 944)
  - Prins, Sonya, 1955, 1969 (Box 73, Folder 945)
  - Ragan, Sam, undated (Box 73, Folder 946)
  - Root, Frances Bowen and Francie at Gulch cabin, Colorado, 1961 (Box 73, Folder 947)
  - Root, Tom, 1970 (Box 73, Folder 948)
  - Ross, Linda and Paul, 1973 (Box 73, Folder 949)
  - Royle, Trevor, 1976 (Box 73, Folder 950)
  - Sherby, John, 1943, 1975 (Box 73, Folder 951)
  - Sherida, Doctor Saleh, 1964 (Box 73, Folder 952)
  - Simpson, Alva A., 1952 (Box 73, Folder 953)
  - Spivey, Kregg, 1974 (Box 73, Folder 954)
  - Sterling, Cary, 1960, 1969 (Box 73, Folder 955)
  - Strick, Elizabeth, 1974 (Box 73, Folder 956)
  - Walker, Mae, 1972 December 24 (Box 73, Folder 957)
  - Unsorted, 1970-1980; 2 (Box 73, Folder 958-959)
- Sound Recordings, 1937-1984; Series VIII; 1.25; (3 boxes)
  This series consists of sound recordings of or relating to Norman Macleod, including audiocassettes, reel-to-reel sound recordings, and 7", 10", and 12" record albums.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Audiocassettes in Box 74: Use of originals is restricted. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  Box 75 (Reel-to-reel audiotape): Restricted Fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  Box 76 (Record Album Storage): Restricted Fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  - "Ahsahta Cassette Sampler" 14 Western Poets read from their Ahsahta volumes, 1983; 1; This audiocassette will not play. It has not been digitized. (Box 74, Item barcode 39002091393976)
    Boise State University
  - Michael Hogan "April 1976", Cold Mountain Press, 1975, 1976; 1; 01:25:15; The audio breaks up at about 00:41:28. (Box 74, Item barcode 39002091393984)
  - Pembroke Magazine on NBC Today Show, 1976 March 26; 1; 00:01:39 (Box 74, Item barcode 39002091393992)
  - "What is creativity?," a forum at Pembroke State College
    - Associated ephemera, 1969 (Box 74, Folder 963)
    - Sound recording, 1969 Spring; 1; 01:11:13; There is high background noise on the tape and the program is distorted at times. (Box 75, Item barcode 39002091394008)
  - Poems by Norman W. Macleod read by Alice Wicklund Mills recorded in 1937 at Mount Holyoke College (Box 76 (Record album storage), Folder 965-967)
    one 7" and two 10" record albums
  - Poems read by Norman W. Macleod at the Library of Congress Division of Music, sound recordings, 1945 (Box 76 (Record album storage), Folder 968-975)
    eight 12" record albums
- Printed Material, 1913-1984; Series IX; 2.5; (6 boxes)
  Includes clippings, newsletters, and ephemera relating to Norman Macleod and to American poetry broadly. Also includes microfilmed versions of printed material.
  - Clippings
    Arranged alphabetically by name of person, organization or title of serial publication. Unsorted clippings are filed at the end.
    - "A-M", 1939-1983; 25 (Box 77, Folder 976-1000)
    - Macleod, Norman W., 1929-1976; 2 (Box 77, Folder 1001-1002)
    - Macleod, Norman W., 1969-1980; 2 (Box 78, Folder 1003-1004)
    - "M-P", 1913-1978; 11 (Box 78, Folder 1005-1015)
    - "P-W", 1954-1983; 15 (Box 79, Folder 1016-1030)
    - Unsorted Clippings, 1983-1984; 4 (Box 79, Folder 1031-1034)
    - Oversize Clippings, 1941-1974
  - Poster for an appearance at Boise State University, undated
  - Poster for Poetry in Public for Ahsahata Press, undated
  - Newsletters relating to American Indians, 1971-1975 (Box 80, Folder 1035)
  - Morang, Alfred, Kiss the Sky for Me, 1959 (Box 80, Folder 1036)
  - Pembroke State University, pamphlets and programs, 1969-1975 (Box 80, Folder 1037)
  - The Magazine of Sigma Chi, 1984 (Box 80, Folder 1038)
  - The University of New Mexico Alumnus, 1970-1971 (Box 80, Folder 1039)
  - Unsorted Printed Material, including ephemera, photocopies of articles, and broadsides, 1937-1978; 4 (Box 80, Folder 1040-1043)
  - Unsorted Printed Material, including ephemera, photocopies of articles, and broadsides (Continued), 1972-1984; 5 (Box 81, Folder 1044-1048)
  - Microfilm, 1973-1980 (Box 82, Folder 1049)
- Scrapbooks, 1935-1953; Series X; 0.67; (4 boxes)
  Arranged chronologically.
  This series consists of scrapbooks created by Norman Macleod to document his life and work, chiefly consisting of clippings referring to his writings or career.
  - Scrapbook, 1935-1941 (Box 83 Oversize, Folder 1050)
  - Scrapbook, 1940-1941 (Box 84 Oversize, Folder 1051)
  - Scrapbook leaves, loose, 1942
  - Scrapbook, 1943-1947 (Box 85 Oversize, Folder 1052)
  - Scrapbook, 1947-1953 (Box 86 Oversize, Folder 1053)
- Oversize Material, 0.17; (2 boxes)
  - Briarcliff Quarterly staff members (Series VII), 1946 (Box 87 (Oversize), Folder 1054)
  - MacDiarmid, Hugh (Series VII), 1974 (Box 87 (Oversize), Folder 1055)
  - Poster for an appearance at Boise State University (Series IX), undated (Box 87 (Oversize), Folder 1056)
  - Poster for Poetry in Public for Ahsata Press (Series IX), undated (Box 87 (Oversize), Folder 1057)
  - Loose leaves from Scrapbooks (Series X), 1942 (Box 87 (Oversize), Folder 1058)
  - Hotvedt, Kris (Series I), 1969-1970 (Box 88 (Oversize), Folder 1059)
  - "Memoir file," photocopies of articles (Series II), undated (Box 88 (Oversize), Folder 1060)
  - Drawing of Norman Griffith Macleod (photocopy of a 1951 drawing) (Series V), undated (Box 88 (Oversize), Folder 1061)
  - Oversize clippings (Series IX), 1969; 2 (Box 88 (Oversize), Folder 1062-1063)
- Restricted Papers, 0.21; (1 box)
  Box 89 (Restricted Papers): Restricted until 2023. Consult the appropriate curator for further information.
  - Outgoing correspondence, unsent, 1979 (Box 89, Folder 1064)
  - Incoming correspondence, 1936, undated; 2 (Box 89, Folder 1065-1066)
  - Third party correspondence, 1945-1970; 5 (Box 89, Folder 1067-1071)
  - Writings, undated (Box 89, Folder 1072)